One bronze piece for a job payment, huh?
That basically means working for free,
but a surprising amount of
adventurers will take it.
We're not doing this just for the money.
Sometimes, we'll take jobs to help people.
Well, the guild wouldn't
take a job request like
"Defeat the Legendary Lord of the Lake."
Any jobs catch your eye?
Sheila?
Don't worry.
I'm not going into the Labyrinth
for a while, just like I promised.
Oh, no... I thought I could help
if you were looking for a quick job.
Great.
Is nobody going to take this quest?
Oh, the one with the single
bronze piece reward?
It's a guild tradition, so everyone
at least thinks about it.
But it's pretty difficult...
Gathering a Dragonblood Flower...
Yeah.
They only bloom next to poisonous swamps.
The story about them is
so wonderful, though...
A dragon fell in love with a human woman...
His blood became a bright red flower
called the Dragonblood Flower.
A rather gruesome story.
Girls who receive that flower
are said to be loved forever.
Well, I have heard that story.
But for this job, they want
it as medicine, right?
Yes. It's a job from the
children at an orphanage.
They say they need the Dragonblood Flower
to save someone they care about.
I see.
Rentt, are you...
Dragonblood
Flower
So this is the place, huh?
It's more run-down than I expected.
Oh...
Oh, right.
I might be able to use the fluids
from that slime to fix it.
Well, that kind of worked...
Coming!
I'm sorry. Headmistress
Lillian isn't in right now.
You'll have to come back another time...
I'm an adventurer. I took
the job at the guild.
Oh, I was sure you were a debt collector.
I see.
Please, come in.
It's a little cramped, but...
Thank you.
Everyone, be on your best behavior.
He's an adventurer.
Wow, you're an adventurer?
Is that sword real?
Are you strong?
Why are you dressed so weird?
Hey! I told you all that adventurers
are dangerous barbarians,
so you needed to stay away from them!
Sorry...
Um, I'm sorry...
I didn't mean you specifically.
No, it actually makes me feel better.
Adventurers can be the rowdy sort.
It's only natural to be cautious.
Listen, everyone.
You need to stay away from
weird-looking adults.
Okay.
They seem like good kids.
I apologize.
It can be dangerous to be too trusting,
but it just shows they've
had a happy upbringing.
Yes! Headmistress Lillian is a great woman!
I mean, a wonderful lady!
You can speak normally around me.
But...
You should be more polite
around adults, yes.
But I don't mind.
You won't get mad later?
Of course not.
My name is Rentt Vivie.
I'm a Bronze-class adventurer.
Bronze? I was sure the best
we'd get was an Iron-class.
You know a lot about us.
Did you make the request?
Yes. My name is Alize.
Then Alize, let's talk about the job.
Dragonblood Flowers aren't easy to get.
I know.
You can barely find them at any stores.
And even if you do, they're very expensive.
But you need one anyway.
Yes.
I want to know more.
All right. But you'll need to keep our secret.
Secret?
I'm sorry I can't get out
of bed to welcome you.
My name is Lillian June. I'm a priestess
of the Eastern Sky Church.
I'm Rentt Vivie. An adventurer.
I'm so glad you're helping to clean
out the orphanage's basement,
even though we can only
pay such a small amount.
Thank you, so much.
Well, it's a good change of pace.
The basement is small, but
monsters do appear down there,
so I can't have the children doing it.
Rest, Headmistress!
I'll tell him the rest.
Thank you, Alize.
Her disease is called Malaccumula.
Malaccumula?
Yes.
She's a divinity user.
But if your divinity isn't strong,
each time you use it there's a reaction that
causes evil energy to accumulate in the body.
It won't kill her anytime soon, but...
I didn't know there was such a thing.
We had a healer look at
her, so it has to be that.
The only way to heal it is with the blood
of a holy maiden, or a special medicine.
I see.
And you need the Dragonblood Flower
to make this special medicine?
Yes.
She doesn't know what her
disease is, does she?
She doesn't.
If she knew, she'd have another
priestess take over the orphanage.
And then she'd leave the orphanage,
and accept the disease
as the will of heaven...
Well, we'll need to get the Dragonblood
Flower before that happens, then.
I was sure nobody would take the job...
You were?
But if that happened, I was going to become
an adventurer and go get it myself!
I've got a little bit of mana, you know.
But you don't have time to learn
how to be an adventurer...
I can really ask you to do it?
Yeah. I'll get it for you. I promise.
Thank you, Rentt!
But first...
I'll clean up that basement.
You don't need to follow me.
No, you're fighting monsters, right?
I don't think it's that fun to watch, but...
You can't use a sword
in a room this cramped.
Take it, just in case.
Okay.
Looks like they're here.
Huh? Really?
Pretty big, for a puchi suri.
What?
It changed color?
This feeling...
Don't tell me...
Spin around three times in a circle.
Rentt, what's that chubby little
black rat on your shoulder?
It joined my party in the
orphanage's basement.
You're skipping a lot there.
Vampires have the power to
make and control familiars.
I didn't know you could do
the same thing, though.
I guess I can.
True. I hadn't actually done any
experiments to see what would happen
if I gave your blood to
another creature yet.
Can I keep him?
Sure, if you want.
We've already got an undead living here.
A rat or two won't change a thing.
He'll have to pay rent, though.
Rent?
I want samples of his blood and hair.
There's a lot I want to try.
And I also want to do an ecology study.
What do you eat?
Hey!
I see. Just like your dad, then.
I guess my blood is quite popular.
Hey, what are you going to call him?
Blackie, 'cause he's black.
You could put a little more thought into it.
Fine. I'll name him.
How about "Edel"?
An excellent name, yes?
It means "Noble One" in the ancient tongue.
I heard you were the leader
of the other puchi suri.
He seems satisfied.
You can communicate with him?
I can't speak his language, but I
can kinda tell what he's thinking.
From now on, then, you're Edel.
And I'm the one who named you.
Hey, I'm your master, okay?
Since I became an undead, I stopped
needing sleep almost entirely.
I thought about never leaving the labyrinth,
but people would get suspicious of an
adventurer that never took any rest.
These hours are so incredibly boring...
Come in.
You're leaving early in the morning, right?
Why not fill your belly, first?
I wonder if it's a sign it'll snow today...
Don't be ridiculous.
I can cook too, you know.
I do know.
Then you know how dangerous the
Tarasque Swamp is too, then.
How did you know where I'm going?
Well, I guess you would.
Of course I do.
That's the only swamp around here where
you can find a Dragonblood Flower.
Yeah.
Are you going alone?
If I go alone, I won't have
to worry about the poison.
There's Tarasque there. A type of wyvern.
Even Bronze-class adventurers
would take a party to go there.
I'm not going to fight.
What?
I bought this for cheap at a roadside stall.
Holy water?
Yes, they do say you can keep Tarasque
away by using holy water, but...
It doesn't always work.
Well, it'll work out.
Listen, you...
It would be a waste to let this get cold.
I'll eat it while it's still hot.
Is it good?
Yeah.
I haven't enjoyed normal food
this much in a long time.
I put a drop of my blood in it.
So that's why...
Like it?
Yeah.
I'll make you another
batch when you get back.
We're here, mister.
Thanks.
This is as far as I can take you.
I'll come and get you this evening.
Thanks.
The poison doesn't bother you?
Well, I can purify it with
my divinity if I have to.
It'll be fine.
The Tarasque Swamp.
It has another name, but nobody uses it.
There are rare animals and plants
that can only be found here,
so it's been made at least passable.
Nobody wants to stick their
foot into a poison swamp.
Monsters found in the wild are stronger
than the ones in the labyrinth.
That's because they use weapons,
or know how to fight in groups.
They're tough opponents, but
now I'm strong enough to...
Easily defeat a few goblins.
Next time, you work, too.
You don't think that you're the master
in this relationship, do you?
Sheesh...
It sure is handy being undead, though!
I have poison resistance, for one thing.
If I could just do something
about my appearance,
I might be willing to
stay like this forever!
I could probably never get married, though.
He jumped and let me fall, the bastard.
I've got some horrible luck today.
I can't let my guard down for a moment.
Are all vampire familiars like this?
Thank you for the meal.
It was delicious.
You liked it?
Rentt certainly enjoyed it.
But isn't Rentt...
I mixed my blood in with it.
Don't worry. Just in his portion.
Anyway, I'm surprised the guild's already
aware of what happened at Tottsu village.
We had to help transport the criminals.
The villagers were very grateful
to the adventurer who helped them.
They refused to say his name no matter
how many times we asked, though.
So you came to talk to him directly?
I assume he wouldn't want to
talk about it at the guild...
Knowing Rentt, he assumed that even
if he was the hero of that story,
any association of him and the word "kidnapping"
would just make people more suspicious.
He can sometimes do things
you'd never expect him to,
but he does know how to
think things through.
You know him well.
I've known him a long time, after all.
Then do you know...?
Know what?
Why becoming a Mythril-class
adventurer is so important to him.
Nope.
I've never heard him talk
about that, actually.
You haven't?
I've been told that adventurers don't
ask each other about their pasts.
Part of it is that I don't
want to get too nosy, but...
you know how he is.
You don't worry?
Even with the job he's on today...
he might have to fight a Tarasque.
What a strange thing to say.
The guild puts a lot of work into
making sure adventurers only take jobs
appropriate for their strength, right?
Of course. We judged him strong enough
for the task before giving it to him.
Then what's the problem?
I'll defer to the opinion of
our talented guild staff.
And what's more...
Even if something does happen...
an adventurer always finds a way, right?
Damn it! I should've known that
holy water was too cheap to work!
A dead end...
I'll have to fight, huh?
Too bad.
Poison won't work on me.
I don't think I can defeat you
with just my mana, either.
It didn't work, huh?
That's not good.
Edel!
Is that divinity? Is he using my power?
Are you okay?
Don't use my divinity without my okay.
That did give me a good hint, though.
I see. A Tarasque's
weakness is divinity.
Yeah. You helped, too.
But I can't field dress it here.
Not when it's this big...
There we go.
I've got bad luck. That's
one thing I'm sure of.
I was pretty sure I'd have
to fight a Tarasque.
Thanks to him, though,
I've learned how to do it.
I can find a lot of rare materials here, too.
I'll come back soon.
Are these all Dragonblood flowers?
Their power is purifying this whole area.
It's safe to take a few more
than I came for, I'm sure.
Oh my. I'm surprised to
see someone else here.
A Strange Man and a Strange Job